## Etki Acilan

# etki@metu.edu.tr | etkiacilan.github.io

### **OBJECTIVE**

Graduate student looking for summer research internships on Power System State & Parameter Estimation research fields.

#### ${f SUMMARY}$

I am a master's student studying under the supervision of Dr. Murat Gol at Middle East Technical University with a major in Electrical Engineering. I am also a Research and Teaching Assistant at the same department. My main research area is Power System State & Parameter Estimation. I have experience in Kalman Filters, other estimators and optimization methods on MATLAB and Python. I have been the teaching assistant for Power System Analysis courses. I have worked on industrial projects where I implemented well-known state estimation tools.

### RESEARCH INTERESTS

Power System Static State Estimation, Power System Dynamic State Estimation, Parameter Estimation

#### **EDUCATION**

# Middle East Technical University

Ankara, Turkey

MSc. Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Power Systems GPA: 3.90/4 September 2019 – July 2022 (Expected) Supervisor: Dr. Murat Gol

### Middle East Technical University

Ankara, Turkev

BSc. Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Power Systems GPA: 3.35/4 September 2015 – June 2019

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Middle East Technical University

Ankara, Turkey

Teaching Assistant, Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering

February 2020 — Present

- Power System Analysis I
- Power System Analysis II
- High Voltage Techniques I & II

# Middle East Technical University

Ankara, Turkey June 2019 — Present

Research Assistant, Power System Analysis Laboratory

• Participated in projects mentioned in Projects section.

Ulusoy Electric Ankara, Turkey

Intern, Production and Quality Control

September 2018 – October 2018

• Observed the production line of MV equipment.

AF-Mercados EMI Ankara, Turkey

Intern, Distribution Network Planning

June 2018 – September 2018

- Worked at Master Plan of First DISCO.
- Modeled distribution networks of four cities on DigSilent Power Factory

### **PROJECTS**

### Implementation of Power Systems SE Algorithms ASELSAN

January 2020 - April 2021 (Expected)

- Implemented traditional WLS-SE, Transformer Tap Estimator, Observability Analysis, and Bad Data Analysis tools on MATLAB considering sparse nature of the matrices.
- Implemented a Very Short-Term Load Forecast Aided WLS Hybrid-SE.
- $\bullet$  Wrote technical reports of Topology Processor and Hybrid-SE.

### Power Plant Parameter Calibration Tool Siemens Turkey

October 2020 - Present

- Implemented Ensemble Kalman Filter based Power Plant Parameter Calibration Algorithm using PSS/E API on Python.
- Presented algorithms on technical meetings.

### ALGORITHMS

• Weighted Least Squares, Kalman Filter, Extended Kalman Filter, Unscented Kalman Filter, Ensemble Kalman Filter, Newton-Raphson Method, Depth-First Search, and other common optimization algorithms such as line search methods.

### **SKILLS**

Programming Language: Python, MATLAB

Simulation and Analysis Software: PSS/E (including psspy), DigSilent PowerFactory

# **COURSES**

- Power System Stability and Dynamics
- Power System Real-Time Monitoring and Control
- System Identification
- Optimization
- Power System Analysis I & II
- Distribution Systems
- Electrical Power Quality Monitoring and Improvement
- Nonlinear Control Systems
- Feedback Systems
- Economic Operation of Power System
- Linear Systems Theory

### **HONORS**

National Academic Personnel and Postgraduate Education Entrance Exam (GRE Equivalent Exam in Turkey)

Ranked 313rd among 119000 participants

Dean's Honor Roll Achieved High Honor Roll 5 times in 8 terms

National University Entrance Exam Ranked 1665th among 2 million participants

# **LANGUAGES**

English Professional working proficiency

 ${\bf Turkish}\ {\it Native}$